# Sudeshna Chaki, PhD

Phone +49 157 336 01647

E-Mail sudeshna.leuven@gmail.com

Portfolio https://tinyurl.com/schaki

# **BIO**

I am a UX designer and anthropologist with extensive experience in designing and conducting qualitative and quantitative research. I specialize in applying ethnography and other anthropological methods to recognize the needs, wants and the broader circumstances of people and translating them into actionable insights which stakeholders can relate to.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

2021

# Independent project - Olive App, Germany UX and UI designer

End-to-end UX design of the Olive app. Designed and conducted surveys and interviews (10 respondents). Created personas, user journeys and site maps. Conducted contextual inquiry, usability tests (10 respondents), A/B testing and card sorting (5 respondents). This was augmented by prototyping, mockups and UI design. Collaborated with other designers via Slack by performing and receiving reviews and feedback.

2020 - current

# Max Planck Institute for Social Anthropology, Germany Research Associate

Presented insights from qualitative and quantitative research in publications (a book chapter is currently in press and a book manuscript is currently being proofread). Disseminated research results in over 15 talks in workshops, seminars and conferences. Collaborated with a culturally diverse team from 7 countries to design surveys and comparatively analyze outcomes.

2014 - 2020

# Max Planck Institute for Social Anthropology, Germany Doctoral Researcher

End-to-end research project management experience. Defined the problem statement, designed and executed the research roadmap. Conducted long term (12 months) ethnographic fieldwork among businesses and small-scale industries. Designed and moderated surveys and interviews among more than 50 respondents in an empathetic and culturally sensitive manner. Analyzed and presented results and insights in the form of dissertation, publications, workshops and conference talks.

2014

#### University of North Bengal, India Research Associate

Conducted ethnographic research, interviews and surveys. Translated results into actionable items for better policy design.

# **EDUCATION**

UX Design	2021
CareerFoundry, Berlin, Germany	
PhD in Social Anthropology Martin Luther University Halle-Wittenberg, Germany and Max Planck Institute for Social Anthropology	2020
Project Management course - Agile Coordination and Organisation with Scrum Comcave College, Halle(Saale), Germany	2019
Masters in Social and Cultural Anthropology KU Leuven, Leuven, Belgium	2013

# **SKILLSET**

Tools Sketch, Figma, InVision, Balsamiq, Usability Hub, Optimal Workshop, SPSS

Languages English, German, Bengali, Hindi, Marathi

# **COMPLETED PROJECTS**

#### **UX design for Olive**

03/2021 - 07/2021

Career Foundry, Germany

- Olive is a health and fitness platform which helps people to track their progress and receive tailored solutions based on existing health conditions.
- I worked on the entire UX design cycle for Olive as part of my CareerFoundry course.
- This included surveys and interviews with groups of 10 people followed by ideation of user personas and mapping user journeys.
- In the next phase I also gained experience in card sorting exercises with random users followed by rapid prototyping and iterative wireframing while conducting 2 moderated usability studies by recruiting 5-10 respondents.
- I translated my research results into reports and delivered a high fidelity prototype of the Olive app, which was supplemented by extensive design language documentation.

#### Dynamics of Emergence, Functioning and (dis)Continuity: Small-scale enterprises in provincial India

03/2015 - 07/2020

Max Planck Institute for Social Anthropology, Germany

- This project was grounded in economic anthropology and was designed to reveal economic decision making among people and private businesses.
- I demonstrated end-to-end project management experience by designing, fielding and reporting on my independent doctoral project over 48 months.
- I gained solid experience in designing and moderating qualitative research by ideating and conducting surveys and interviews among 40+ small and large privately owned companies and 50+ respondents.
- I conducted ethnographic fieldwork in 4 new locations in India for 12 months where I used my skills as a self-starter and proactive networker to recruit people in my study according to criteria which matched my research goals.
- Based on this data, I comfortably discussed my research results with a multinational team of peers in the form of workshops, publications, seminars and book chapters.

# Deforestation and Land Alienation: Living on the Edge - a study on an endangered tribe

06/2014 - 08/2014

North Bengal University, India

- In this project, I worked as a research coordinator and communicator.
- I conducted interviews and surveys, and worked to support my team
- I also polished my database management skills during this time.

## The Pursuit of a Livable Identity: aspirations and pathways for social mobility among the Namasudras

12/2012 - 03/2013

KU Leuven, Belgium

- This project was part of my MS thesis where I conducted ethnographic investigations on a social group with a specific identity.
- During the 2 month long fieldwork, where I conducted surveys and interviews among 30+ people, I demonstrated empathy and my ability to listen while at the same time being an energetic conversation starter.
- At the end of this project, I successfully translated my results into concise and compelling arguments in an extensive report that showed clear insights into their mindset and reasons for prioritising certain behaviours.

# **AWARDS**

- Recipient of the highly competitive **Erasmus Mundus Fellowship** from the European Union for pursuing a master's degree at KU Leuven, Belgium.
- Worked as a project member in a distinguished **European Research Council** funded project for my doctoral research at the leading European institute for Social anthropology research in Germany.